Simon Flexner Papers 1891-1946 Mss.B.F365
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Simon Flexner Papers, 1891-1946; 115.5 linear feet
  - Murphy, James B., 1915-1939; 10 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his work on x-ray effects on chicken cancer and on chicken spleen extract to determine origins and development of blood cells. Letter to SF on type of organization needed to conduct cancer research; suggests expansion of his laboratory with employment of specialized team of researchers rather than relying on other RIMR departments, 12/11/27. Administrative correspondence on training of Army Medical Corps doctors, May-July, 1918. Report of his laboratory to RIMR Board of Directors, on X-ray stimulation of lymphocytes and cancer tissues and effects of ultraviolet rays on antigenic property of bacteria, November 1918-January 1919. Letters from SF during Murphy's illness February-June, 1920. General administrative correspondence on RIMR. Report of work of Murphy's laboratory of use of X-ray treatment on chronic infections associated with lymphoid overgrowth in tonsils, 10/19/20. Administrative correspondence. Letter to SF concerning plans for cancer research program at RIMR, especially need for a first-class physical chemist, 4/8/22. Report on activities of Dr. Mais in his department for 1922-1923. Letters concerning his wish to observe cancer research in England and to visit English supporters of career "germ theory," 1925. General and administrative correspondence. Outline of research in Murphy's laboratory for 1927. Report to SF on his visit to Europe, 1927. Correspondence on his work on filterable agent in chicken tumors. Administrative correspondence. Correspondence on his wish to expand cancer research into genetics of cancer. Administrative correspondence, 1933-1939.
  - Murphy, Joseph D.
  - Murphy, Julia B.
  - Murphy, Marion
  - Murphy, Robert Cushman
  - Murphy, Starr J.
  - Murphy, William P.
  - Murray, Alfred
  - Murray, Cecil D.
  - Murray, E. G. D.
  - Murray, George Welwood
  - Murray, Gilbert D.
  - Murray, Henry Alexander, Jr.
  - Murray, J. A.
  - Murray, M.
  - Murray, M. A., and Son
  - Murray, Mary
  - Murray, Peter
  - Murray, T. J.
  - Murrich, Mayfair M.
  - Murrow, Edward R.
  - Murtland, Anna A.
  - Muschenheim, Carl
  - Museum of Modern Art, (NYC)
  - Muskogee Laboratory
  - Muslow, Frederick William
  - Musselman, Luther K.
  - Mussen, Aubrey T.
  - Musser, John Herr, Jr.
  - Mussey, R. D.
  - Myers, Burton D.
  - Myers, Charles W.
  - Myers, Henry L.
  - Myers, L. G.
  - Myers, Morton
  - Myers, Victor Carl, 1923-1924; ca. 20 items
    Includes: Administrative correspondence of Society of Experimental Biology and Medicine.
  - Myres, M. J.
  - Myrick, Hannah G.
  - Nachumi, Dr.
  - Nadle, Isidor
  - Nador, George
  - Naeff, J.
  - Naegeli, Otto
  - Nagayo, Mataro
  - Nager, F. R.
  - Nagle, James F.
  - Nakahara, Waro
  - Nakajima, Hisashi
  - Nakano, Suketoshi
  - Naleche
  - Nall, James O.
  - Nalle, Eleanor Ritchie
  - Nam, Benjamin
  - Naon, R. S.
  - Nasalized Tubercular Monkeys
  - Nash, Roy
  - Nashville City Hospital
  - Nasi, Prof.
  - Nasmith, George G.
  - Natamura, T.
  - Nathan, Chester J.
  - Nation, The
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1914-1942; 22 folders
    General, NAS Folders Include: Administrative correspondence about establishing NAS Proceedings, 1914. Minutes of Joint Meeting of Council of NAS and Executive Committee of National Research Council, 1/18/18. Membership lists, programs, circulars, financial statements, etc. Minutes of Executive Committee meetings, May, June, 1938, June 1942. Government Relations and Science Advisory Committee Folder Includes: Statement of NAS policy with reference to Federal interest in scientific education and research, May 1937.
    - [NAS], 8 folders
    - Annual Meeting, 1935
    - Annual Meeting, 1937
    - Executive Committee: Folder 1, 1936-1937
    - Executive Committee: Folder 2, 1936-1937
    - Government Relations and Science Advisory Committee, 1936-1937
    - Hektoen, Ludwig (Ballots)
    - Members and Committees: Folder 1, June 1, 1932
    - Members and Committees: Folder 2, Oct. 2, 1933
    - Members and Committees: Folder 3, July 1, 1934
    - Members and Committees: Folder 4, July 1, 1935
    - Members and Committees: Folder 5, July 1, 1936
    - Members and Committees: Folder 6, July 11, 1937
    - Report on Role of Science in National Planning, June 1934
    - Treasurer's Report, August 1938
  - National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis
  - National Civic Federation
  - National Committee For Mental Hygiene
  - National Conference of Jews and Christians
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - National Dairy Council
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Inc.
  - National Geographic Magazine
  - National Geographic Society
  - National Health Council
  - National Instttute of Health
  - National Insititute of Social Sciences
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild
  - National Public Housing Conference
  - National Research Council (NRC), 1916-1945; 43 folders
    Includes: Medical Fellowship Board, Minutes of (first) meeting, 4/18/22. Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, Minutes, Tanuary 1927, April 1927, and January 1928, including lists of fellows, research subjects, amount of grants, dates completed. List of members of Council of NBC, 1916. General correspondence, form letters, administrative materials, etc. Report to Division of Educational Relations on Dean Seashore's visit to colleges and universities on the Pacific Coast, 1925. Transcript of remarks by William H. Welch at meeting of Committee on Policies, 4/24/32. Chart of reorganized structure of NRC in 1932. Copies of letters from Drs. Howell, Jewett, Lillie and D. K. Compton on reorganized structure of NRC. Minutes of meeting of Executive Committee of Division of Medicine and Related Sciences, 1918-19. Minutes of first meeting of Division of Medical Sciences, June 1919. Correspondence on the organization of NRC during WWI. Minutes of second meeting of Executive Board of war organization of NRC jointly with NAS, March 1918. Summary of discussion on borderlands in science, at a meeting of administrative committee of NRC, April 1935. Transcripts or conference on patent policies, 3/29/35. Financial statements, 1919. Miscellaneous reports to NRC. Fellowship materials. Minutes of NRC Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, various dates, 1919-1934. Summary of NRC fellows, July 1921, July 1932. Annual Reports of NRC Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, 1922 and 1923. Outline of functions of NRC Fellowships in Physics, Chemistry, Mathematies, and Medical Sciences and Biological Sciences, 1929. Minutes of Advisory Committee on Fellowships, 1935, 1936. Draft of plan for Promotion of Research in Physics and Chemistry in Cooperation with Educational Institutions, submitted to Rockefeller Foundation and NRC, 1919. Outlines of proposals for a National Institute of Physical and Chemical Research, 1919. [Some folders not well organized.] Fellowship Board folders include: Report of Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, 1929. Summary of appropriations of Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, 1919-1929. Summary of activities of grant recipients, 1928-1929. Agenda of meeting of Fellowship Board in Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics, April 1932. Science Advisory Board folders include: Administrative materials, memoranda, minutes. Report to President of the United States, 1934 ("Putting Science to Work for the National Welfare"). Miscellaneous special Advisory Board reports, mainly cooperation between scientific institutions and industry. 1934-1935.
    - [NRC], 3 folders
    - Correspondence: Folder 1, 1916-1925
    - Correspondence: Folder 2, 1929-1936
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 1, 1919-1929
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 2, 1919-1929
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 3, 1928-1929
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 4, 1928-1929
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 5, 1932
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 6, 1932
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 7, 1935
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 8, 1935
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 9, 1932
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 10, 1932
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 11, 1932
    - Fellowship Board: Folder 12, 1932
    - Fellowships, 7 folders
    - Financial, 2 folders
    - Minutes, 2 folders
    - Miscellaneous
    - Reports, 5 folders
    - Science Advisory Board: Folder 1, 9 folders
  - National Research Fund, 1928-1930; 1 folder
    Includes: Letters to T. H. Morgan and Vernon Kellogg (copies) in reply to a request for suggestions for research that could be significantly advanced by National Research Fund; correspondents include: J. J. Abel, E. J. Cohn, E. N. Harvey, John Auer, P. G. Benedict, E. O. Jordan, and Selig Hecht. List of grant recipients, 1928. Minutes of meetings of Scientific Committee of National Research Fund, 1928.
  - National Resources Board
  - National Tuberculosis Association
  - National University of Ireland
  - National Vaccine and Antitoxin Institute
  - Natt, Inez M.
  - Nature
  - Naughton, J. G
  - Navarini, Emilio P.
  - Navy Department
  - Neaderland, Herman
  - Neail, H. W.
  - Neal, Josephine B.
  - Neal, M. Pinson
  - Neal, N. W.
  - Neal, Phil H.
  - Neal, T. A.
  - Neale, A. V.
  - Neale, Horatio
  - Needham, James E.
  - Needles, R. J.
  - Neely, N. C.
  - Neergaard, Dr. von
  - Neesen, Victor
  - Nef, John Ulric, 1913-1914; 8 items
    Includes: Correspondence about his application for a Carnegie Institution grant.
  - Neff, Andrew
  - Neff, Frank C.
  - Neff, George W.
  - Neff, James S.
  - Neff, Mary Lawson
  - Neill, James M.
  - Neill, William, Jr.
  - Neilson, Thomas R.
  - Neilson, William A.
  - Neisser, Max
  - Neithercut, R.
  - Nelbach, George J.
  - Nelson, Aven
  - Nelson, Casper I.
  - Nelson, Harvey B.
  - Nelson, J. M.
  - Nelson, John
  - Nelson, Kent
  - Nelson, Knute
  - Nelson, M. R.
  - Nelson, N. A.
  - Nesbit, Charles T.
  - Neter, Erwin
  - Netter, Dr.
  - Netter, Arnold, 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1913-1915
    - Folder 2, 1916-1919
    - Folder 3, 1920-1934
  - Netter, Leon
  - Neuban, William M.
  - Neuberg, Carl, 1921-1929; 11 items
    Includes: Correspondence on exchange of reprints.
  - Neufeld, Frederick, 1924-1935; ca. 40 items
    Includes: Correspondence on his proposed visit to the United States, 1926. Proposal to SF that Rockefeller Foundation contribute funds towards new buildings of Koch Institut, 1931. General correspondence.
  - Neuhaus, C. E.
  - Neuman, Alfred
  - Neuman, George
  - Neumann, Felix
  - Neumann, Henry
  - Neumann, R. O.
  - Neun, Dora E.
  - Neurad, Adolph
  - Neurad, Hermine
  - Neurad, Jeannette
  - Neurological Institute
  - Neustaedter, Marcus
  - Neville, Linda
  - Nevils, Coleman
  - Nevin, Mary
  - Nevins, Allan
  - Newburger, Mrs.
  - Newburgh, L. H.
  - Newcomb, Simon
  - Newcomer, Harry S.
  - Newell, Mrs. J. P.
  - Newell, John M.
  - Newell, Lyman C.
  - Newell, Wilmon
  - New England Association of Chemistry Teachers
  - New England Journal of Medicine
  - New Era Printing Co.
  - New France
  - New Friends of Music
  - New Hampshire Motor Vehicle Dept.
  - New Jersey State Agricultural Experiment Station
  - Newland, Sarah J.
  - Newlands, Bill
  - Newman, Barclay M.
  - Newman, Sir George
  - Newman, George R.
  - Newman, Henry
  - Newman, R. W.
  - Newman, Samuel
  - Newman Drug Co.
  - New Republic
  - New School for Social Research
  - News Items - Publicity, 2 folders
  - Newsholme, Sir Arthur
  - Newton, Mrs. F. J. Jr.
  - Newton, Mrs. L. R.
  - Newton, Richard C.
  - Newton, S. B.
  - New York Academy of Medicine, 1914-1937; ca. 30 items
    Includes: General administrative correspondence.
  - New York Assembly
  - New York City Cancer Committee
  - New York City Committee on Plan and Survey
  - New York City Department of Health, 10 items (Dept. of Health)
    Dept. of Health folder includes: Circular letter on the cause and prevention of cerebrospinal meningitis. Statistics of mortalities from cerebrospinal meningitis in New York City, 1906-08. Receipts for shipments of antimeningitis serum from RIMR to Department of Health.
    - [Dept. of Health], 1908-1925
    - Loose Milk Commission
    - Milk Commission
  - New York Committee on After Care of Infantile Paralysis
  - New York Evening Post
  - New York Hospital
  - New York Infirmary for Women and Children
  - New York Medical Journal
  - New York Pathological Society
  - New York Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild
  - New York Post-Graduate Medical School and Hospital
  - New York Society of Tropical Medicine
  - New York Staats-Zeitung
  - New York (State)
    Department of Health folders include: Report from director of Department's Pathology Laboratory on organization and scope of activities, 1914. General correspondence. Health Commission folder includes: General administrative correspondence. Commission's final report on public health nursing, 1931. Report of Commission's Committee on Medical Care, 1931.
    - Ass'n of Public Health Laboratories: Abstracts of Papers and Summaries of Discussions, 1939
    - Commission on Alcoholic Beverage Control Legislation
    - Committee National Defense
    - Department of Health, 1914-1944; 3 folders
    - Department of Health: Division of Sanitation
    - Department of Health: Public Health Council
    - Department of Motor Vehicles
    - Health Commission, 1930-1931; ca. 40 items
    - Joint Committee on Unemployment Relief
    - Sanitary Officers Association
  - New York State Constitution
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs
  - New York State Roosevelt Memorial
  - New York Times
  - New York University
  - (New York) Varieties
  - New York World
  - News Items [re: Simon Flexner]
  - Neylor, K. F.
  - Nice, Charles M.
  - Nichol, Kenneth D.
  - Nicholas, Cassie
  - Nicholas, Warren W.
  - Nicholas and Harris
  - Nicholls, Albert George
  - Nicholls, Norah
  - Nichols, Estes
  - Nichols, Henry J.
  - Nichols, Ward
  - Nicholson, A. M.
  - Nicholson, Frederic M.
  - Nicholson, Jesse Thompson
  - Nicholson, John T.
  - Nickel, Margaret C.
  - Nicolay, S.
  - Nicoll, Matthias, Jr., 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1916-1922
    - Folder 2, 1923-1924
    - Folder 3, 1926-1929
    - Folder 4, 1930-1935
  - Nicolle, C.
  - Nicolle, M., 2 folders
  - Nicolson, W. P., Jr.
  - Niebergall, Margaret W.
  - Niederle, Frieda
  - Niemeyer, Charles V.
  - Niemeyer, Reinder
  - Niflot, Helen
  - Nigg, Clara
  - Niles, Walter L.
  - Nilson, Arthur R.
  - Nippon Yusen Kaisha
  - Nipps, Ruby W.
  - Niscemi, Princess Margaret di
  - Nishibe, Masujiro
  - Nissen, H. A.
  - Noakes, Frank
  - Nobecourt, P.
  - Nobel-Committee, Medical
  - Nobel Peace Prize Committee
  - Noble, Edmund
  - Noble, Emily
  - Noble, G. Kingsley
  - Noble, Robert E.
  - Noble, W. C.
  - Noc, F.
  - Nocht, Bernhard
  - Noe, Adolf Carl von
  - Noguchi, Hideyo, 9 folders
    Includes: General administrative correspondence, 1914-1924. Most of the correspondence relates to his work with Yellow Fever Comissions of the International Health Board to Ecuador, Brazil and the Gold Coast, intermittently 1918-1928. Folders include reports of his bacteriological laboratories and their day-to-day work. Correspondence on his work with neosalvarsan as a bacteriocide, 1919.
    - Folder 1, 1913-1917
    - Folder 2, 1917-1919
    - Folder 3, Jan.-May 1920
    - Folder 4, Jun.-Dec. 1920
    - Folder 5, 1921-1922
    - Folder 6, 1923-May 1924
    - Folder 7, Jun. 1924-Dec. 1930
    - "Oroya Fever"
    - Biography
  - Noguchi, Isamu
  - Noguchi, Mary
  - Nolan, B. J.
  - Nolan, H. O.
  - Nolf, P.
  - Nonesuch Press
  - Noonan, Julia A.
  - Noone, A. T.
  - Nordhoff, Walter
  - Nordhoff-Jung, Sofie A.
  - Norfolk Protestant Hospital
  - Norgord, C. P.
  - Norlin, Campbell F. G.
  - Norman, W. H.
  - Norman, Remington Co.
  - Norrington, H. George
  - Norris, Agnes
  - Norris, Charles
  - Norris, H. C. R.
  - Norris, James F.
  - Norris, James U.
  - Norris, Mary Hope
  - North, Charles E.
  - North, Ernest Dressel
  - North, Frank Mason
  - North American Review
  - North China Union Language School
  - Northrop, G. N.
  - Northrop, John Howard, 4 folders
    Includes: Jacques Loeb's recommendation of Northrop to work at RIMR in chemistry, 7/19/15. General administrative correspondence on RIMR. Some correspondence on his work on production of acetone by bacterial action, 1918. Letter to SF criticizing work of Anson and Mirsky on hemoglobin, 6/12/31. Memorandum to SF on his production of a form of crystalline pepsin, 5/12/29.
    - Folder 1, 1915-1925
    - Folder 2, 1926-1933
    - Folder 3, 1934-1940
    - Folder 4, 1926-1941
  - Northrup, William
  - Northrup, William P.
  - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Co.
  - Norton, Charles D.
  - Norton, Mrs. Charles F.
  - Norton, E. A.
  - Norton, John F.
  - Norton, Polly
  - Norton, Rupert
  - Norton, Warder W.
  - Norwood, Carlisle
  - Nourse, Mary L.
  - Nouy, Pierre Lecomte du
  - Novy, Frederick George, 1913-1936; 26 items
  - Nowlin, Nadine
  - Noyes, Arthur Amoss, 1914-1928; 2 folders
    Includes: Correspondence concerning publication of National Academy of Sciences Proceedings, 1914. Copy of "Proposal for Endowment of Research in Physics arid Chemistry" by Hale and Milliken, given to SF to present to Executive Committee of Rockefeller Foundation, June 1918. Copy of announcement of the establishment of NRC fellowships in physics and chemistry, supported by Rockefeller Foundation, March 1919. "Plans for Promotion of Research in Physics and Chemistry," report prepared by Research Fellowship Committee of NRC, May 1920. Letter to SF on his discussion with Milliken, Hale, G. N. Levis on possible development of a central research institute of physics and chemistry, with alternative methods of accomplishing similar research goals through cooperation with universities, 3/6/20. Copy of letter from G. N. Lewis on his recommendations to National Research Fund for most effective use of funds for pure research which would compete with financial inducements offered by industry, 5/18/28.
  - Noyes, C. Reinold
  - Noyes, Clara D.
  - Noyes, Marcia C.
  - Noyes, William Albert
  - Noyes, Winthrop G.
  - Nudelman, Harry M.
  - Nukada, S.
  - Nunez, M. F.
  - Nungester, W. J.
  - Nutrition Laboratory: Carnegie Institution of Washington
  - Nuttall, George H. Falkner
  - Nutting, Miss A.
  - Nutting, G. K.
  - Nuzum, Frank R.
  - Nuzum, John W.
  - Nye, Robert N.
  - Oates, F. F.
  - Ober, Frank R.
  - Ober, Harlan F.
  - Ober, Ralph Beverley
  - Oberholtzer, Ernest C.
  - Oberly, H. S.
  - Obert, Edward H.
  - Oberwager, John
  - O'Boyle, Mrs. P. F.
  - O'Brien, B.
  - O'Brien, D. D.
  - O'Brien, Daniel P.
  - O'Brien, Edward
  - O'Brien, Morgan J.
  - O'Brien, R. A.
  - O'Byrne, Frederick
  - Ochs, Adolph S.
  - Ochsner, Albert J.
  - O'Connell, Joseph J.
  - O'Connor, F. W.
  - O'Connor, John P.
  - O'Connor, R. Page
  - O'Connor, Roderic
  - O'Connor, T. P.
  - Odell, H. E.
  - Odell, Helen R.
  - Odena, Frank M.
  - Odenthal, H. J.
  - Odin, G.
  - Odriozola, Ernesto
  - Oehschhlager, William G.
  - Oertel, Horst
  - Oesterreichishe Gesellschaft fur Seuchenbekampfung
  - Oettinger, Bernard
  - Ogata, T.
  - Ogden, Henry Neely
  - Ogden, Mahlon D.
  - Ogden, Rollo
  - Ogg, W. R.
  - O'Hanlon, George L.
  - Ohio, State Board of Health
  - Ohio State Journal
  - Ohio, State Medical Association
  - Ohio State University. College of Medicine
  - Ohira, Tokuzo
  - Okada, S.
  - Okawa, S.
  - O'Keeffe, John G.
  - Okrent, Samuel
  - Olbrycht, Thaddeus
  - Olcott, George P., Jr.
  - Olcott, George T.
  - Olcott, Mary
  - Oldman, Julius
  - Olenik, J. L.
  - Olin, J. D.
  - Olin, R. M.
  - Olinger, George W.
  - Olitsky, Peter K., 7 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on his work with Dr. Chickering at U. S. Naval Base, Portsmouth, Va., on meningitis victims, 1917-1918. Report on meningitis carriers, U. S. Naval Hospital, Portsmouth, Va., June-August 1917. Correspondence and reports to SF from China when Olitsky was working in outbreaks of meningitis, May-June 1918. Comments by SF on some of Olitsky's papers and work with antidysenteric serum and influenza serum. Correspondence on Olitsky's work with plant mosaic virus, successfully cultivated by him in a test tube, March 1925. Correspondence on Olitsky's foot and mouth disease expedition to Europe for U.S.D.A., May 1925-June 1926. Correspondence on Olitsky's work on virus diseases with Florence R. Sabin at RIMR, 1934-1939. General administrative correspondence on RIMR.
    - Folder 1, 1917-Mar. 1918
    - Folder 2, Apr.-Dec. 1918
    - Folder 3, 1919-1922
    - Folder 4, 1923-1925
    - Folder 5, 1926-1929
    - Folder 6, 1930-1933
    - Folder 7, 1935-1945
  - Olive, Edgar W.
  - Oliver, J. C.
  - Oliver, Jean
  - Oliver, L. W.
  - Oliver, Wade W.
  - Olivier, Charlotte
  - Olivo, Olivero Mario
  - Olmstead, Hazel R.
  - Olmstead, M. P.
  - Olmstead, Margaret S.
  - Olmsted, Ingersoll
  - O'Loughlin, Colman S.
  - Olpp, G.
  - Oman, Dr.
  - O'Melveny, H.W.
  - Omi, Kaoru
  - O'Neil, Michael
  - O'Neal, W. R.
  - Onis, Federico de
  - Openchowski, M. W.
  - Ophuls, William
  - Opie, Eugene Lindsay, 1915-1941; ca. 60 items
    Includes: Correspondence about chairs of bacteriology, 1919 and of pathology, 1920, Washington University. Correspondence on Ortto Meyerhof's visit to United States, 1923. General correspondence, including mention of Opie's work with insulin and tuberculosis.
  - Oppenheimer, Bernard S.
  - Oppenheimer, Ella
  - Oppenheimer, Franz
  - Oppenheimer, Seymour
  - Original Protocols: Monkeys, 1909-1912; 17 folders
    Includes: Records of meningitis experiments in SF's laboratory at RIMR.
    - Folder 1, 1-50
    - Folder 2, 51-100
    - Folder 3, 101-150
    - Folder 4, 151-200
    - Folder 5, 201-250
    - Folder 6, 251-300
    - Folder 7, 301-350
    - Folder 8, 351-400
    - Folder 9, 401-450
    - Folder 10, 451-500
    - Folder 11, 501-550
    - Folder 12, 551-600
    - Folder 13, 601-650
    - Folder 14, 651-700
    - Folder 15, 701-750
    - Folder 16, 751-800
    - Folder 17, 801-849
  - Orchard, John E.
  - Orcutt, Marion L.
  - Ordman, David
  - Ordway, Thomas
  - Oregonian
  - O'Reilley, Henry F.
  - O'Reilly, Myles
  - Orlando, Joseph
  - Orloff, Sam
  - Ormond, A. T.
  - Orndorf, W. R.
  - Ornstein, Arthur
  - Ornstein, Otto
  - O'Rourke, Sarah G.
  - Orr, Gilbert M.
  - Orr, John B.
  - Orr, Paul F.
  - Orr, William A.
  - Ornsburn, H. K.
  - Orth, Johannes
  - Orthopedic Hospitals
  - Ortiz, Manuel
  - Ortner, Norbert
  - Orton, Samuel T.
  - Orton, William A.
  - Ory, Mrs. C
  - O'Ryan, John F.
  - Osborn, F. A.
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1915-1930; ca. 30 items
    Includes: General correspondence concerning American Museum of Natural History.
  - Osborn, L. Perry
  - Osborn, Minott A.
  - Osborn, Stanley H.
  - Osborn, William Church
  - Osborne, F. B.
  - Osborne, Oliver T.
  - Osborne, Raymond W.
  - Osborne, Thomas B.
  - Oser, Mrs.
  - Osgood, Robert B.
  - Oshbaugh, R. A.
  - O'Shea, M. V.
  - Osler, Britton
  - Osler, Grace R.
  - Osler, Sir William, 1914-1920; ca. 40 items
    Includes: Correspondence concerning financial aid given by Rockefeller Foundation to Belgian professors, 1914. Correspondence on supply of antimeningitis serum to England, 1915. General correspondence.
  - Osnato, Michael
  - Ospina, Guillermo
  - Osten, Anna L. von der
  - Oster, Katherine E.
  - Osterhout, Anna M.
  - Osterhout, Winthrop John Van Leuven, 1927-1941; ca. 40 items
    Includes: General correspondence about RIMR. Correspondence on his work on bioelectrical phenomena, 1933.
  - Osterman, A. G.
  - Osterheimer, Alfred J.
  - O'Sullivan, A. G.
  - O'Sullivan, Mary Isabelle
  - Otamendi, Rafael
  - Otis, Elmer F.
  - Ottawa Civic Hospital
  - Ottenberg, Reuben